Guide to the Le Bayou Records
University of Houston Libraries
- Subscriptions, 1934-1963
  - Service d’Echange, 1937-1963
    - Le Sol Clair; France, 1947, 1949, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - Soleil; Algérie, 1950-1953 (Box 10, Folder 157)
    - South Central Bulletin, 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - Statistique, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - Stratus; Amiens, France, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 160)
    - La Table Round, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Les Temps Modernes; Paris, France, 1946, 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 162)
    - Temoignage Chretien; Paris, France, 1946-1952 (Box 10, Folder 163)
    - Le Thyrse; Bruxelles, Belgique, 1947, 1949, 1950, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - La Tour de Feu; France, 1947-1948, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 165)
    - Tuillieries; Paris, France, 1950-1952 (Box 10, Folder 166)
    - La Vie Franco Américaine; New Hampshire, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - La Voix de France; New York, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 168)
    - Yggdrasill; Paris, France, 1937-1947 (Box 10, Folder 169)
    - La Wallonie; Liège, Belgique, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 170)
    - General Service d’Echange; Bimonthly, 1947-1963 (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - General Service d’Echange; Monthly, 1947-1963 (Box 10, Folder 172)
    - General Service d’Echange; Quarterly, 1947-1963 (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - Subscription Companies, 1941-1963
    This subseries consists of 9 folders that contain materials that relates to subscription companies. Some individuals, universities, and organizations ordered their subscriptions through services that provided a large selection, rather than directly ordering from Le Bayou. It is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
    - American News Company; Waco, Texas, 1949-1962 (Box 10, Folder 174)
    - Bay State Periodical Service; Boston, Massachusetts, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 175)
    - Franklin Square Agency; New Jersey, 1950-1951, 1954-1955, 1957-1959, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 176)
    - F.W. Faxon and Company; Boston, Massachusetts, 1941-1946, 1948-1952, 1955-1956, 1958, 1960-1963 (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - H.W. Wilson Company; New York, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - Moore-Cottrell Subscription Agencies, Inc.; New York, 1949, 1951, 1953, 1958-1959, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 179)
    - Stechert-Hafner, Inc.; New York, 1960-1963 (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - Subscriptions; Miscellaneous, 1946, 1950-1956, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - Subscription Services; Miscellaneous, 1948, 1952-1958, 1961, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 182)
  - Additional Subscription Information, 1947-1963
    This sub-series contains subscription information in the form of an index card file. It includes both the subscription information of individual people and organizations. This series is organized alphabetically.
    - Subscription Index Cards, 1947-1963 (Box 16, Item 1)
- Le Petite Théâtre Français, 1934-1938
  This series consists of 10 folders that contain materials that relate to Le Petit Théâtre Français, including office documents, and copies of its publication La Gazette. Le Petit Théâtre Français was a French theater organization started by Jules Vern. This subseries is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
  - Documents, 1936-1938 (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - Miscellaneous, 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 184)
  - Vouchers, 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 185)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Le Petit Théâtre Français de Houston - La Gazette du Petit Théâtre, no.15, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
  - Le Petit Théâtre Français de Houston - La Gazette du Petit Théâtre, no.19, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Le Petit Théâtre Français de Houston - La Gazette du Petit Théâtre, no.24, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Le Petit Théâtre Français de Houston - La Gazette du Petit Théâtre, no.32, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Livre d’Or, 1950-1959
  This series consists of 12 folders that contain original and duplicate copies of a scrapbook of clippings relating to Le Bayou and its publicity, from 1950 to 1959. For each original copy, which is organized by date, there is a duplicate copy. This series is organized by date.
  - Originals
    - 1950 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - 1951 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - 1952 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - 1953 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - 1955 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - 1956 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 1957 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 1958 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 1959 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Duplicates
    - 1950 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - 1951 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - 1952 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - 1953 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - 1953 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - 1956 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 1957 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 1958 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1959 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Journals, 1933-1963
  This series consists of 2 subseries that consist of Éditions du Bayou and Journals Received. Each subseries is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
  - Éditions du Bayou, 1933-1961
    This subseries consists of 16 folders that consist of Éditions de Bayou, a publication series that published small books of poetry, and smaller notebook versions of Le Bayou. This series is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
    - Ballades Louisianes - Bourgeois, André, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Ballades du Texas - Sulver, Jean, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Ballades de Mon Bayou - Sulver, Jean, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - En Marge des Saisons: Poèmes - Robert, Michel, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Pastels et Sanguines - Chantal, René, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Swing: Poèmes de Jean Sulver, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Swing: Poèmes de Jean Sulver, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Vers Casses - Sulver, Jean, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Epreuves du Bayou, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Le Bayou, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Le Bayou - Cahier dix-neuf (19), 1943 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Le Bayou - Cahier dix-neuf (19), 1943 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Le Bayou - Cahier vingt-et-un (21), 1943 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Le Bayou - Cahier vingt-deux (22), 1944 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Le Bayou no.87, Automne 1961 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Le Bayou no.64, Hiver 1955 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Le Bayou - Tables of Contents nos.40-80, 1945-1951 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Journals Received, 1940-1963
    This subseries consists of 11 folders containing journals that Le Bayou either received in exchange from other publications, or were sent in hopes of such an exchange. This series is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
    - Common Ground - New York, 1940, 1942, 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Ecrits de Paris: Revue des Questions Actuelles, 1964 Mai, 1964 Juillet-Aout (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Entretiens Avec Mon Dentiste; Édition de l’Occident; Oppitz, René; Belgique, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - La Lyre de David - Club des Jeunes Talents, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Le Chemin des Hommes - Bancal, Jean - Apollinaire/Éditions André Silvaire, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Les Oiseaux Foudroyés - Kerchore, Arnold de, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Liturgies Flamandes - Looten, Emmanuel, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Poème de la Patience de l’Univers - Linze, Georges - Liège, Belgique, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Nouvelles Éditions Debresse - Paris, France - Au Jour le Jour; Perez, Diego; Préface de Tristan Maya, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Nouvelles Éditions Debresse - Paris, France; A Ta Louange; de Albergaria, Jacinto Soares, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Nouvelles Éditions Debresse - Paris, France; Éclos la Nuit; Comiti, Jean-Baptiste, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Nouvelles Éditions Debresse - Paris, France; Ciel et Fumée; Cluchier, Alice, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 37)
- Artistic Stamps
  This series contains two small boxes of handcarved rubber stamps used in the production of Le Bayou.
  - Handcarved Rubber Stamps; 13a (Box 13, Item 1)
  - Handcarved Rubber Stamps; 13b (Box 13, Item 2)
- Ledgers, 1940-1953
  This series contains two ledgers of financial information and one receipt book. This series is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
  - Accounts (Closed), 1940-1953 (Box 14, Item 1)
  - 1946-1956 (Box 14, Item 2)
  - Receipt Book, 1945-1946 (Box 14, Item 3)
- Photographic Material, 1935
  This series contains photographs of members of the Le Bayou staff and includes formal portraits of its founder, Jules Verne. It also contains two photo albums and one scrapbook with photographs of the Le Bayou staff at work and at play. This series is organized by date.
  - Photographs; Portraits, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Photo Albums; 15a, undated (Box 15, Item 1)
  - Photo Albums; 15b, undated (Box 15, Item 2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1935 (Box 15, Item 3)